losif V.

Software Engineer

London, UK

in iosify 🞧 iosify 🚵 iosify

I am a Senior Software Engineer with experience in creating complete projects from scratch to production in Node.js and Laravel. I write code as clean as possible so that the next dev will be happy to maintain it and the junior will quickly grasp it. Curious by nature, I'm always learning new things.

SKILLS

Languages			Frame	Frameworks			Admin		
Node.js	Typescript	PHP	Laravel	Express	Serverless	AWS	Terraform	CI / CD	
Solidity	bash		Hardhat	Hardhat			Docker Shell Scripting		

Currently learning

Java NextJS T3 Stack

WORK EXPERIENCE (5)

Aug 2018 - Current

Contractor Software Engineer at Casa4 (own LTD)

Contractor for various clients through my own LTD. Worked on diverse projects, specializing in PHP, Laravel, and Node.js. Involved both in team-based development and solo application building from design to deployment.

- ElectroRent: Wrote Laravel code to fix bugs and to add new features for a tool-renting platform.
- Aliat Optic: Designed and produced an invoicing app, integrating external FTP data via AWS Lambda and DynamoDB. This application was successfully used in production for about 3 years with minimal bugfixes.
- Hurlingham Club: Managed system migration to internal servers, resolving a wide range of dev-ops issues.
- TicketTailor: Enhanced the API of a large PHP application with both bugfixes and new features.
- → Technologies: Laravel, Node.js, AWS Lambda, MySQL, Terraform, AWS, VueJS, NextJS, CLI, Bash

Mar 2022 - Current

Information Technology Advisor (part time) at Artetra

Startup that works towards bringing NFT's into online virtual galleries.

- As an acting CTO, I work to translate the business requirements into project features
- Responsible with the application architecture and sometimes with smaller granular tasks. I'm managing a team of 3-4 developers and I have to provide them with any assistance when they need it.
- → Technologies: Node.js, Hardhat, Solidity, AWS

Oct 2020 - Aug 2022

Software Engineer at True Compliance

Cloud Based Compliance Management System.

- Built the main API of the system and contributed in designing the ecosystem's architecture. Contributed to all the adjacent applications which were deployed as serverless functions on AWS with Laravel Vapor.
- Notable projects assigned solely to me: A reporting app. which would create a report from any SQL provided; A bespoke real time caching system which saved processed relational data into a no-sql db.
- → Technologies: PHP, Laravel, Laravel Vapor, AWS, VueJS, Node.js, Serverless Framework, CLI, Bash

Oct 2018 - Oct 2019

Software Engineer at Skin Analytics

Designing and developing our main applications and maintaining the AWS infrastructure.

- Biggest task was the migration from a no-sql database to a relational database which resulted in a 11x speed increase. I achieved this with no change to the frontend or the end user's journey.
- → Technologies: Node.js, Express.js, TypeScript, AWS, Loopback, pm2, Angular

Feb 2017 - Jun 2018

PHP Application Developer / Dev-Ops at Woooba

The only Backend Engineer in the company, I was designing, developing & supporting client applications.

- Developed & maintained nationwide educational platforms. Designed and integrated various APIs.
- I built a complete financial management application with Laravel and Vue.
- Managed all our DigitalOcean droplets with a CI setup on Forge.
- → Technologies: Laravel, DigitalOcean, Laravel Forge, PHP, RESTful APIs, MySql, Git, CLI, VueJS, PhpUnit.

PROJECTS (2) -

CLI Path

Simple CLI tool to search paths on google maps (Serverless Framework, Auth0, OpenAPI, VHS)

Casa4 website

https://casa4.co.uk/

An overengineered personal website built for learning purposes (Hugo, Terraform, Cloudfront, AWS, GHA)

EDUCATION (2) -

2010 - 2012

Masters Management and Business Engineering at Technical University of Cluj-Napoca

2004 - 2009

Masters Computer Science at Technical University of Cluj-Napoca

INTERESTS

Hobbies

Chess HiFi Music

Motorcycles Photography